[
{"Front": "あいかわらず", "Back": "as ever,as usual,the same", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アイデア/アイディア", "Back": "idea", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あいまい", "Back": "vague,ambiguous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遭う", "Back": "to meet,to encounter (undesirable nuance)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "扇ぐ", "Back": "to fan,to flap", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "青白い", "Back": "pale,pallid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あかんぼう", "Back": "baby", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明き", "Back": "room,time to spare,emptiness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あきれる", "Back": "to be amazed,to be shocked", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アクセント", "Back": "accent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あくび", "Back": "yawn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飽くまで", "Back": "to the end,to the last,stubbornly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "明け方", "Back": "dawn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "揚げる", "Back": "to lift,to fry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "挙げる", "Back": "to raise,to fly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あげる (=やる)", "Back": "to do for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "憧れる", "Back": "to long for,to yearn after,to admire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "足跡", "Back": "footprints", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "味わう", "Back": "to taste,to savor,to relish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "預かる", "Back": "to keep in custody,to receive on deposit,to take charge of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暖まる", "Back": "to warm up,to get warm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暖める", "Back": "to warm,to heat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あたりまえ", "Back": "usual,common,ordinary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あひら", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あちらこちら", "Back": "here and there", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "厚かましい", "Back": "impudent,shameless,brazen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "圧縮", "Back": "compression,condensation,pressure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宛名", "Back": "address,direction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あてはまる", "Back": "to be applicable,to come under (a category),to fulfill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あてはめる", "Back": "to apply,to adapt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "暴れる", "Back": "to act violently,to rage,to struggle,to be riotous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脂", "Back": "fat,tallow,lard", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あぶる", "Back": "to scorch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あふれる", "Back": "to flood,to overflow,to brim over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雨戸", "Back": "sliding storm door", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "甘やかす", "Back": "to pamper,to spoil", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "余る", "Back": "to remain,to be left over,to be in excess,to be too many", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "編物", "Back": "knitting,web", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "編む", "Back": "to knit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "危うい", "Back": "dangerous,critical,grave", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "怪しい", "Back": "suspicious,dubious,doubtful", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "荒い", "Back": "rough,rude,wild", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "粗い", "Back": "coarse,rough", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あらすじ", "Back": "outline,summary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "争う", "Back": "to dispute,to argue,to be at variance,to compete", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "改めて", "Back": "another time,again,over again,anew,formally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "改める", "Back": "to change,to alter,to reform,to revise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "著す", "Back": "to write,to publish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有難い", "Back": "grateful,thankful,welcome,appreciated,evoking gratitude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "在る", "Back": "to live,to be", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あれこれ", "Back": "one thing or another,this and that,this or that", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あわただしい", "Back": "busy,hurried,confused,flurried", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "あわてる", "Back": "to become confused", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "安易", "Back": "easy-going", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "案外", "Back": "unexpectedly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "アンテナ", "Back": "antenna", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "言い出す", "Back": "to start talking,to speak,to tell,to propose,to suggest,to break the ice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "言い付ける", "Back": "to tell,to tell on (someone),to order", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "意義", "Back": "meaning,significance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生き生き", "Back": "vividly,lively", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いきなり", "Back": "(uk) abruptly,suddenly,all of a sudden,without warning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "育児", "Back": "childcare,nursing,upbringing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幾分", "Back": "somewhat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生け花", "Back": "(1) flower arrangement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "以後", "Back": "after this,from now on,hereafter,thereafter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "以降", "Back": "on and after,hereafter,thereafter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "イコール", "Back": "equal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勇ましい", "Back": "brave,valiant,gallant,courageous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "衣食住", "Back": "necessities of life (food, clothing, etc.)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "意地悪", "Back": "malicious,ill-tempered,unkind", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いちいち", "Back": "one by one,separately", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一応", "Back": "once,tentatively,in outline,for the time being", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一段と", "Back": "greater,more,further,still more", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一流", "Back": "first class,top grade,foremost,top-notch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "佚", "Back": "be lost,peace,hide,mistake,beautiful,in turn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一昨日", "Back": "day before yesterday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一昨年", "Back": "year before last", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一斉", "Back": "simultaneous,all at once", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一旦", "Back": "once,for a moment,one morning,temporarily", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一定", "Back": "fixed,settled,definite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いっていらっしゃい", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いってらっしゃい", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いってまいります", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いつのまにか", "Back": "before one knows,unnoticed,unawares", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "移転", "Back": "moving,transfer,demise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "井戸", "Back": "water well", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "緯度", "Back": "latitude (nav.)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "従姉妹", "Back": "cousin (female)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "威張る", "Back": "to be proud,to swagger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嫌がる", "Back": "to hate,to dislike", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "いよいよ", "Back": "more and more,all the more,increasingly,at last,beyond doubt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煎る", "Back": "to parch,to fry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "炒る", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "入れ物", "Back": "container,case,receptacle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "インキ", "Back": "ink", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "インタビュー", "Back": "interview", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引力", "Back": "gravity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ウーマン", "Back": "woman", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ウール", "Back": "wool", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ウエートレス", "Back": "waitress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "植木", "Back": "garden shrubs,trees,potted plant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飢える", "Back": "to starve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浮ぶ", "Back": "to float,to rise to surface,to come to mind", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浮かべる", "Back": "to float,to express,to look (sad, glad)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浮く", "Back": "to float,to become merry,to become loose", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "承る", "Back": "(hum) to hear,to be told,to know", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "受取", "Back": "receipt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "受け持つ", "Back": "to take (be in) charge of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "薄暗い", "Back": "dim,gloomy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "薄める", "Back": "to dilute,to water down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "打合せ", "Back": "business meeting,previous arrangement,appointment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "打ち消す", "Back": "to deny,to negate,to contradict", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "討つ", "Back": "to attack,to avenge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "うっかり", "Back": "carelessly,thoughtlessly,inadvertently", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "映す", "Back": "to project,to reflect,to cast (shadow)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "写る", "Back": "to be photographed,to be projected", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "映る", "Back": "to be reflected,to harmonize with,to come out (photo)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "うどん", "Back": "noodles (Japanese)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有無", "Back": "yes or no,existence,flag indicator (comp),presence or absence marker", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "埋める", "Back": "to bury,to fill up,to fill (a seat, a vacant position)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "敬う", "Back": "to show respect,to honour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "裏返す", "Back": "to turn inside out,to turn (something) over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "裏口", "Back": "backdoor,rear entrance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "占う", "Back": "to forecast,to predict", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恨み", "Back": "resentment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恨む", "Back": "to curse,to feel bitter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "羨ましい", "Back": "envious,enviable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "羨む", "Back": "to envy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "売上", "Back": "amount sold,proceeds", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "売り切れ", "Back": "sold-out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "売り切れる", "Back": "to be sold out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "売行き", "Back": "sales", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "うろうろ", "Back": "loiteringly,aimless wandering", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "運河", "Back": "canal,waterway", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "うんと", "Back": "a great deal,very much", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "英文", "Back": "sentence in English", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "英和", "Back": "English-Japanese (e.g. dictionary)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ええと", "Back": "let me see,well,er....", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "液体", "Back": "liquid,fluid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "エチケット", "Back": "etiquette", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "絵の具", "Back": "colors,paints", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "エプロン", "Back": "apron", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "偉い", "Back": "great,celebrated,eminent,terrible,awful,famous,remarkable,excellent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宴会", "Back": "party,banquet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "園芸", "Back": "horticulture,gardening", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "演劇", "Back": "play (theatrical)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "円周", "Back": "circumference", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遠足", "Back": "trip,hike,picnic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "延長", "Back": "extension,elongation,prolongation,lengthening", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煙突", "Back": "chimney", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "追い掛ける", "Back": "to chase or run after someone,to run down,to pursue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "追い越す", "Back": "to pass (e.g. car),to outdistance,to outstrip", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "オイル", "Back": "oil,engine oil,kerosene", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "応援", "Back": "aid,assistance,help,reinforcement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "王女", "Back": "princess", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "応ずる", "Back": "to answer,to respond,to meet,to satisfy,to accept", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "応接", "Back": "reception", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "応対", "Back": "receiving,dealing with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "往復", "Back": "(col) round trip,coming and going,return ticket", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "欧米", "Back": "Europe and America,the West", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "応用", "Back": "application,put to practical use", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "オーケストラ", "Back": "orchestra", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おおざっぱ", "Back": "rough (not precise),broad,sketchy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大通り", "Back": "main street", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "オートメーション", "Back": "automation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "オーバーコート", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大凡", "Back": "about,roughly,as a rule,approximately", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お帰り", "Back": "return,welcome", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おかけください", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おかげさまで", "Back": "Thanks to god,thanks to you", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おかず", "Back": "side dish,accompaniment for rice dishes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拝む", "Back": "to worship,to beg,to make a supplication", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お代わり", "Back": "second helping,another cup", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "補う", "Back": "to compensate for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おきのどくに", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "屋外", "Back": "outdoors", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おくさん", "Back": "(hon) wife,your wife,madam", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "送り仮名", "Back": "part of word written in kana", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おげんきで", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "怠る", "Back": "to neglect,to be off guard,to be feeling better", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "押える", "Back": "to stop,to restrain,to seize,to repress,to suppress,to press down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おさきに", "Back": "before,ahead,previously", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "納める", "Back": "to obtain,to reap,to pay,to supply,to accept", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "治める", "Back": "(1) to govern,to manage,(2) to subdue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "惜しい", "Back": "regrettable,disappointing,precious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御辞儀", "Back": "bow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伯父さん", "Back": "middle-aged gentleman,uncle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小父さん", "Back": "middle-aged gentleman,uncle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "叔父さん", "Back": "middle-aged gentleman,uncle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おしゃれ", "Back": "smartly dressed,someone smartly dressed,fashion-conscious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おじゃまします", "Back": "Excuse me for disturbing you", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "教わる", "Back": "to be taught", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おだいじに", "Back": "Take care of yourself", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "落着く", "Back": "to calm down,to settle down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御手洗", "Back": "font of purifying water placed at entrance of shrine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お出掛け", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お手伝いさん", "Back": "maid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おどかす", "Back": "to threaten,to coerce", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "落し物", "Back": "lost property", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おととい", "Back": "day before yesterday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おととし", "Back": "year before last", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おとなしい", "Back": "obedient,docile,quiet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "驚かす", "Back": "to surprise,to frighten,to create a stir", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おねがいします", "Back": "please", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "各々", "Back": "each,every,either,respectively,severally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伯母さん", "Back": "(hon) aunt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "叔母さん", "Back": "(1) aunt,(2) middle-aged lady", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おはよう", "Back": "(abbr) Good morning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "お参り", "Back": "worship,shrine visit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おまたせしました", "Back": "Sorry to have kept you waiting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おまちください", "Back": "Please wait a moment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おまちどおさま", "Back": "Sorry to have kept you waiting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おめでたい", "Back": "happy event,matter for congratulation,auspicious event,pregnancy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "思い掛けない", "Back": "unexpected,casual", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "思い込む", "Back": "to be under impression that,to be convinced that", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "思いっ切り", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "思い付く", "Back": "to think of,to hit upon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重たい", "Back": "heavy,massive,serious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おやすみ", "Back": "(1) holiday,absence,rest,(2) (exp) Good night", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "おやつ", "Back": "(1) between meal snack,afternoon refreshment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "親指", "Back": "thumb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "オルガン", "Back": "organ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "卸す", "Back": "to sell wholesale,grated (vegetables)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恩恵", "Back": "grace,favor,blessing,benefit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "温室", "Back": "greenhouse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "温泉", "Back": "spa,hot spring,onsen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "温帯", "Back": "temperate zone", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御中", "Back": "and Company,Messrs.", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "女の人", "Back": "woman", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蚊", "Back": "mosquito", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カーブ", "Back": "(1) curve,(2) curve ball (baseball)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貝", "Back": "shell,shellfish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "開会", "Back": "opening of a meeting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "会館", "Back": "meeting hall,assembly hall", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "改札", "Back": "examination of tickets", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "解散", "Back": "breakup,dissolution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "海水浴", "Back": "sea bathing,seawater bath", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "回数", "Back": "number of times,frequency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "回数券", "Back": "book of tickets", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "改正", "Back": "revision,amendment,alteration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "快晴", "Back": "good weather", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "解説", "Back": "explanation,commentary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "改造", "Back": "(1) remodeling,(2) modding (comp)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "開通", "Back": "opening,open", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "回転", "Back": "rotation,revolution,turning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "解答", "Back": "answer,solution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "回答", "Back": "reply,answer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "外部", "Back": "the outside,external", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "解放", "Back": "release,liberation,emancipation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "開放", "Back": "open,throw open,liberalization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "海洋", "Back": "ocean", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "概論", "Back": "intro,outline,general remarks", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "帰す", "Back": "to send back", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "却って", "Back": "on the contrary,rather,all the more,instead", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "代える", "Back": "to exchange,to interchange,to substitute,to replace", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反る", "Back": "to warp,to be warped,to curve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "家屋", "Back": "house,building", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "係わる", "Back": "to concern oneself in,to have to do with,to affect,to influence,to stick to (opinions)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "書留", "Back": "writing down,putting on record,recording,making a note of,registration (of mail)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "書取", "Back": "dictation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "垣根", "Back": "hedge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掻く", "Back": "to scratch,to perspire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "嗅ぐ", "Back": "to sniff,to smell", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "架空", "Back": "aerial,overhead,fiction,fanciful", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "各自", "Back": "individual,each", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拡充", "Back": "expansion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学術", "Back": "science,learning,scholarship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "各地", "Back": "every place,various places", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拡張", "Back": "expansion,extension,enlargement,escape (ESC)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "角度", "Back": "angle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学年", "Back": "year in school,grade in school", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学部", "Back": "department of a university,undergraduate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "格別", "Back": "exceptional", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "確率", "Back": "probability", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学力", "Back": "scholarship,knowledge,literary ability", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掛け算", "Back": "multiplication", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "可決", "Back": "approval,adoption (e.g. motion, bill),passage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "火口", "Back": "a burner,origin of a fire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下降", "Back": "downward,descent,fall,drop,subsidence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重なる", "Back": "to be piled up,lie on top of one another,overlap each other", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重ねる", "Back": "to pile up,to put something on another,to heap up,to add,to repeat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飾り", "Back": "decoration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "火山", "Back": "volcano", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "かしこまりました", "Back": "certainly!", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貸し出し", "Back": "lending,loaning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "過失", "Back": "error,blunder,accident", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "果実", "Back": "fruit,nut,berry.", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貸間", "Back": "room to let", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貸家", "Back": "house for rent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "個所", "Back": "passage,place,point,part", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "過剰", "Back": "excess,over-", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "かじる", "Back": "to chew,to bite (at),to gnaw,to nibble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "課税", "Back": "taxation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下線", "Back": "underline,underscore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カセット", "Back": "cassette (tape)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "加速", "Back": "acceleration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "加速度", "Back": "acceleration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "固い", "Back": "stubborn,firm (not viscous or easily moved)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "堅い", "Back": "hard (esp. wood),steadfast,honorable,stuffy writing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "片仮名", "Back": "katakana", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "片付く", "Back": "to put in order,to dispose of,to solve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "塊", "Back": "lump,mass,clod,cluster", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "固まる", "Back": "to harden,to solidify,to become firm,to become certain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "片道", "Back": "one-way (trip)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傾く", "Back": "to incline toward,to slant,to lurch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "片寄る", "Back": "to be one-sided,to incline,to be partial", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学科", "Back": "study subject,course of study", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学会", "Back": "scientific society,academic meeting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "楽器", "Back": "musical instrument", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "学級", "Back": "grade in school", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "担ぐ", "Back": "to shoulder,to carry on shoulder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "括弧", "Back": "parenthesis,brackets", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "活字", "Back": "printing type", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "活躍", "Back": "activity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "活力", "Back": "vitality,energy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仮定", "Back": "assumption,supposition,hypothesis", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "過程", "Back": "process", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "課程", "Back": "course,curriculum", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仮名", "Back": "(n) alias,pseudonym,pen name", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仮名遣い", "Back": "kana orthography,syllabary spelling", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鐘", "Back": "bell,chime", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "加熱", "Back": "heating", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "兼ねる", "Back": "to hold (position),to serve,to be unable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カバー", "Back": "cover (ex. book)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "過半数", "Back": "majority", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "被せる", "Back": "to cover (with something)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "釜", "Back": "iron pot,kettle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "紙屑", "Back": "wastepaper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "神様", "Back": "god", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "剃刀", "Back": "razor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ガム", "Back": "chewing gum", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貨物", "Back": "cargo,freight", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "かゆい", "Back": "itchy,itching", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歌謡", "Back": "song,ballad", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "殻", "Back": "shell,husk,hull,chaff", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カラー", "Back": "collar,color,colour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "からかう", "Back": "to ridicule,to tease,to banter with,to make fun of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "空っぽ", "Back": "empty,vacant,hollow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "かるた", "Back": "(n) playing cards (pt: carta)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "枯れる", "Back": "to wither,to die (plant),to be blasted (plant)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "カロリー", "Back": "calorie", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "かわいがる", "Back": "to love,to be affectionate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乾かす", "Back": "to dry (clothes, etc.),to desiccate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "渇く", "Back": "to be thirsty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "為替", "Back": "money order,exchange", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "瓦", "Back": "roof tile", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "代る", "Back": "(v5r,vi) to take the place of,to relieve,to be substituted for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "間隔", "Back": "space,interval,SPC", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "換気", "Back": "ventilation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感激", "Back": "deep emotion,impression,inspiration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "関西", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鑑賞", "Back": "appreciation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感ずる", "Back": "to feel,to sense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "間接", "Back": "indirection,indirectness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乾燥", "Back": "dry,arid,insipid,dehydrated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "感想", "Back": "impressions,thoughts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "観測", "Back": "observation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寒帯", "Back": "frigid zone", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勘違い", "Back": "misunderstanding,wrong guess", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "官庁", "Back": "government office,authorities", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "缶詰", "Back": "packing (in cans),canning,canned goods,tin can", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乾電池", "Back": "dry cell,battery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "関東", "Back": "eastern half of Japan, including Tokyo", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "観念", "Back": "(1) idea,notion,conception,(2) sense (e.g. of duty)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乾杯", "Back": "toast (drink)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "看板", "Back": "sign,signboard,doorplate,poster", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "看病", "Back": "nursing (a patient)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冠", "Back": "crown,diadem,first,best", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "漢和", "Back": "Chinese Character-Japanese (e.g. dictionary)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気圧", "Back": "atmospheric pressure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "器械", "Back": "instrument", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "着替え", "Back": "changing clothes,change of clothes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "機関車", "Back": "locomotive,engine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飢饉", "Back": "famine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "器具", "Back": "utensil", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "期限", "Back": "term,period", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "記号", "Back": "symbol,code", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刻む", "Back": "to mince,to carve,to engrave", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "儀式", "Back": "ceremony,rite,ritual,service", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "基準", "Back": "standard,basis,criteria,norm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "規準", "Back": "standard,basis,criteria,norm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "起床", "Back": "rising,getting out of bed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "着せる", "Back": "to put on clothes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "基礎", "Back": "foundation,basis", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気体", "Back": "vapour,gas", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "基地", "Back": "base", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "きっかけ", "Back": "chance,start,cue,excuse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぎっしり", "Back": "tightly,fully", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "基盤", "Back": "foundation,basis", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "客席", "Back": "guest seating", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "客間", "Back": "parlor,guest room", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ギャング", "Back": "gang", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "キャンパス", "Back": "campus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "休業", "Back": "closed (e.g. store),business suspended,shutdown,holiday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "休講", "Back": "lecture cancelled", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "休息", "Back": "rest,relief,relaxation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "給与", "Back": "allowance,grant,supply", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "休養", "Back": "rest,break,recreation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "清い", "Back": "clear,pure,noble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強化", "Back": "strengthen,intensify,reinforce,solidify", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "境界", "Back": "boundary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "行事", "Back": "event,function", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恐縮", "Back": "shame,very kind of you,sorry to trouble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "教養", "Back": "culture,education,refinement,cultivation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "行列", "Back": "(1) line,procession,(2) matrix (math)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "漁業", "Back": "fishing (industry)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "曲線", "Back": "curve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "規律", "Back": "order,rules,law", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "斬る", "Back": "(v5r) to behead,to murder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気を付ける", "Back": "to be careful,to pay attention,to take care", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "金魚", "Back": "goldfish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "区域", "Back": "limits,boundary,domain,zone,sphere,territory", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "偶数", "Back": "even number", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "空想", "Back": "daydream,fantasy,fancy,vision", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "空中", "Back": "sky,air", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "クーラー", "Back": "cooler,air conditioner", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "釘", "Back": "nail", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "区切る", "Back": "to punctuate,to cut off,to mark off,to stop,to put an end to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "櫛", "Back": "comb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "くしゃみ", "Back": "sneeze", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "苦情", "Back": "complaint,troubles,objection", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "苦心", "Back": "pain,trouble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "屑", "Back": "waste,scrap", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "崩す", "Back": "to destroy,to pull down,to make change (money)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "薬指", "Back": "ring finger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "崩れる", "Back": "to collapse,to crumble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "砕く", "Back": "to break,to smash", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "砕ける", "Back": "to break,to be broken", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "くたびれる", "Back": "to get tired,to wear out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "くだらない", "Back": "good-for-nothing,stupid,trivial,worthless", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下る", "Back": "to get down,to descend", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "唇", "Back": "lips", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "口紅", "Back": "lipstick", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "くっつく", "Back": "to adhere to,to keep close to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "くっつける", "Back": "to attach", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "くどい", "Back": "verbose,importunate,heavy (taste)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "句読点", "Back": "punctuation marks", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "配る", "Back": "to distribute,to deliver", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "工夫", "Back": "labourer,worker", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "区分", "Back": "division,section,classification", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "組合せ", "Back": "combination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "組み立てる", "Back": "to assemble,to set up,to construct", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "汲む", "Back": "(1) to draw (water),to dip,to scoop,to pump", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "酌む", "Back": "to serve sake", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悔しい", "Back": "regrettable,mortifying,vexing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悔やむ", "Back": "to mourn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "クリーニング", "Back": "cleaning,dry cleaning,laundry service", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "くるむ", "Back": "to be engulfed in,to be enveloped by,to wrap up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "くれぐれも", "Back": "repeatedly,sincerely,earnestly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "咥える", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "郡", "Back": "country,district", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "稽古", "Back": "practice,training,study", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "敬語", "Back": "honorific,term of respect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蛍光灯", "Back": "fluorescent lamp,person who is slow to react", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "形式", "Back": "form,formality,format,math expression", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "継続", "Back": "continuation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "毛糸", "Back": "knitting wool", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "経度", "Back": "longitude", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "系統", "Back": "system,family line,geological formation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "芸能", "Back": "public entertainment,accomplishments,attainments", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "競馬", "Back": "horse racing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "警備", "Back": "defense,guard,policing,security", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "形容詞", "Back": "true adjective", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "形容動詞", "Back": "adjectival noun,quasi-adjective", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "外科", "Back": "surgical department", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "毛皮", "Back": "fur,skin,pelt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "激増", "Back": "sudden increase", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下車", "Back": "alighting,getting off", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下旬", "Back": "month (last third of)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下水", "Back": "drainage,sewage,ditch,gutter,sewerage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "削る", "Back": "to cut down little by little,to take a percentage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "桁", "Back": "column,beam,digit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下駄", "Back": "geta (Japanese footwear),wooden clogs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "血圧", "Back": "blood pressure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "血液", "Back": "blood", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "月給", "Back": "monthly salary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傑作", "Back": "masterpiece,best work,boner,blunder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "月末", "Back": "end of the month", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "気配", "Back": "indication,market trend,worry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下品", "Back": "vulgarity,meanness,indecency,coarseness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煙い", "Back": "smoky", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蹴る", "Back": "to kick", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "けれど/けれども", "Back": "but,however", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "険しい", "Back": "inaccessible place,sharp eyes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見学", "Back": "inspection,study by observation,field trip", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "謙虚", "Back": "modesty,humility", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原稿", "Back": "manuscript,copy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原産", "Back": "place of origin,habitat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原始", "Back": "origin,primeval", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "研修", "Back": "training", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "厳重", "Back": "strict,rigour,severe,firm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "謙遜", "Back": "humble,humility,modesty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "県庁", "Back": "prefectural office", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "限度", "Back": "limit,bounds", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "現に", "Back": "actually,really", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "顕微鏡", "Back": "microscope", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原理", "Back": "principle,theory,fundamental truth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "原料", "Back": "raw materials", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "碁", "Back": "Go (board game of capturing territory)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恋しい", "Back": "(1) dear,beloved,darling,(2) yearned for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "請う", "Back": "to ask,to request", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "工員", "Back": "factory worker", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強引", "Back": "overbearing,coercive,pushy,forcible,high-handed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公害", "Back": "public nuisance,pollution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "高級", "Back": "high class,high grade", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公共", "Back": "public,community,public service,society,communal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "工芸", "Back": "industrial arts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "孝行", "Back": "filial piety", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交差", "Back": "cross", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "講師", "Back": "lecturer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "工事", "Back": "construction work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公式", "Back": "formula,formality,official", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "口実", "Back": "excuse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "こうして", "Back": "thus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "校舎", "Back": "school building", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公衆", "Back": "the public", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "香水", "Back": "perfume", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公正", "Back": "justice,fairness,impartiality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "功績", "Back": "achievements,merit,meritorious service,meritorious deed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "光線", "Back": "beam,light ray", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "高層", "Back": "upper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "構造", "Back": "structure,construction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交替", "Back": "alternation,change,relief,relay,shift", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "耕地", "Back": "arable land", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交通機関", "Back": "transportation facilities", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "校庭", "Back": "campus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "肯定", "Back": "positive,affirmation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "高度", "Back": "altitude,height,advanced", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "高等", "Back": "high class,high grade", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合同", "Back": "combination,incorporation,union,amalgamation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "後輩", "Back": "junior (at work or school)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公表", "Back": "official announcement,proclamation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鉱物", "Back": "mineral", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "公務", "Back": "official business,public business", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "項目", "Back": "item", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "紅葉", "Back": "(1) (Japanese) maple", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合理", "Back": "rational", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交流", "Back": "alternating current,intercourse,(cultural) exchange,intermingling", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "合流", "Back": "confluence,union,linking up,merge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "効力", "Back": "effect,efficacy,validity,potency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "超える", "Back": "to exceed,to cross over,to cross", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コース", "Back": "course", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コーラス", "Back": "chorus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "焦がす", "Back": "to burn,to scorch,to singe,to char", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国王", "Back": "king", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国籍", "Back": "nationality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "国立", "Back": "national", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ごくろうさま", "Back": "Thank you very much for your....", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "焦げる", "Back": "to burn,to be burned", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "凍える", "Back": "to freeze,to be chilled,to be frozen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心当たり", "Back": "having some knowledge of,happening to know", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心得る", "Back": "to be informed,to have thorough knowledge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "腰掛け", "Back": "seat,bench", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "腰掛ける", "Back": "to sit (down)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "五十音", "Back": "the Japanese syllabary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "胡椒", "Back": "pepper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "こしらえる", "Back": "to make,to manufacture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "超す", "Back": "to cross,to pass,to tide over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "擦る", "Back": "to rub,to chafe,to file,to frost (glass),to strike (match)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ごぞんじですか", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "個体", "Back": "an individual", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御馳走", "Back": "feast,treating (someone)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ごちそうさま", "Back": "feast", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "こちらこそ", "Back": "it is I who should say so", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小遣い", "Back": "personal expenses,pocket money,spending money,incidental expenses,allowance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コック", "Back": "(1) cook (nl:),(2) tap,spigot,faucet,cock", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "こっそり", "Back": "stealthily,secretly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "古典", "Back": "old book,classics,classic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "琴", "Back": "Koto (Japanese harp)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "言付ける", "Back": "to send word,to send a message", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "言葉遣い", "Back": "speech,expression,wording", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "こないだ", "Back": "the other day,lately,recently", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御無沙汰", "Back": "not writing or contacting for a while", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "こぼす", "Back": "to spill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "こぼれる", "Back": "to overflow,to spill", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "塵芥", "Back": "trash,rubbish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ゴム", "Back": "gum,rubber,eraser", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御免", "Back": "your pardon,declining (something),dismissal,permission", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ごめんください", "Back": "May I come in?", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小指", "Back": "little finger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "こらえる", "Back": "to bear,to stand,to endure,to put up with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "娯楽", "Back": "pleasure,amusement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "御覧", "Back": "(hon) look,inspection,try", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コレクション", "Back": "(1) collection,(2) correction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "転がす", "Back": "to roll", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "転がる", "Back": "to roll,to tumble", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "紺", "Back": "navy blue,deep blue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コンクール", "Back": "contest (fr: concours)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コンクリート", "Back": "concrete", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "混合", "Back": "mixing,mixture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "コンセント", "Back": "(1) consent,(2) concentric", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "献立", "Back": "menu,program,schedule", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "こんばんは", "Back": "good evening", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "サークル", "Back": "circle,sports club (i.e. at a company)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "在学", "Back": "(enrolled) in school", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "再三", "Back": "again and again,repeatedly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "祭日", "Back": "national holiday,festival day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "催促", "Back": "request,demand,claim,urge (action),press for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "採点", "Back": "marking,grading,looking over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "災難", "Back": "calamity,misfortune", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "裁縫", "Back": "sewing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "材木", "Back": "lumber,timber", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "サイレン", "Back": "siren", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逆さ", "Back": "reverse,inversion,upside down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逆様", "Back": "inversion,upside down", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捜す", "Back": "to search,to seek,to look for", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遡る", "Back": "to go back,to go upstream,to make retroactive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "酒場", "Back": "bar,bar-room", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "さきおととい", "Back": "two days before yesterday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先程", "Back": "some time ago", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "裂く", "Back": "to tear,to split", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "索引", "Back": "index,indices", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作者", "Back": "author,authoress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "削除", "Back": "elimination,cancellation,deletion,erasure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作成", "Back": "frame,draw up,make,producing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作製", "Back": "manufacture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "探る", "Back": "to search,to look for,to sound out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "囁く", "Back": "to whisper,to murmur", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刺さる", "Back": "to stick,to be stuck", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "匙", "Back": "spoon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "座敷", "Back": "tatami room", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "差し支え", "Back": "hindrance,impediment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "差し引き", "Back": "deduction,subtraction,balance,ebb and flow,rise and fall", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刺身", "Back": "sliced raw fish", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刺す", "Back": "to pierce,to stab,to prick,to thrust", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "挿す", "Back": "to insert,to put in,to graft,to wear in belt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "注す", "Back": "to pour (drink),to serve (drinks)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "射す", "Back": "to shine,to strike", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "流石", "Back": "clever,adept,good,expectations,as one would expect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "撮影", "Back": "photographing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雑音", "Back": "noise (jarring, grating)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "さっさと", "Back": "quickly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "早速", "Back": "at once,immediately,without delay,promptly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "錆", "Back": "rust (colour)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "錆びる", "Back": "to rust,to become rusty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "座布団", "Back": "cushion (Japanese)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冷ます", "Back": "to cool,to dampen,to let cool", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "妨げる", "Back": "to disturb,to prevent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冷める", "Back": "to become cool,to wear off,to abate,to subside", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "さようなら", "Back": "good-bye", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "再来月", "Back": "month after next", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "再来週", "Back": "week after next", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "再来年", "Back": "year after next", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "サラリーマン", "Back": "salary man,company employee", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "騒がしい", "Back": "noisy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "さわやか", "Back": "fresh,refreshing,invigorating", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "三角", "Back": "triangle,triangular", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "算数", "Back": "arithmetic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "酸性", "Back": "acidity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "産地", "Back": "producing area", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "サンプル", "Back": "sample", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "山林", "Back": "mountain forest,mountains and forest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仕上がる", "Back": "to be finished", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しあさって", "Back": "two days after tomorrow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "シーズン", "Back": "season (sporting)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "シーツ", "Back": "sheet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寺院", "Back": "temple", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しいんと", "Back": "silent (as the grave),(deathly) quiet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自衛", "Back": "self-defense", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "塩辛い", "Back": "salty (taste)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "司会", "Back": "chairmanship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "四角", "Back": "square", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "四角い", "Back": "square", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "時間割", "Back": "timetable,schedule", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "四季", "Back": "four seasons", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "敷地", "Back": "site", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "至急", "Back": "urgent,pressing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "敷く", "Back": "to spread out,to lay out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "茂る", "Back": "to grow thick,to luxuriate,to be luxurious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "持参", "Back": "bringing,taking,carrying", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "磁石", "Back": "magnet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "四捨五入", "Back": "rounding up (fractions)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "始終", "Back": "continuously,from beginning to end", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自習", "Back": "self-study", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "静まる", "Back": "to quieten down,to calm down,to subside", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "姿勢", "Back": "attitude,posture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自然科学", "Back": "natural science", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "時速", "Back": "speed (per hour)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "子孫", "Back": "descendants,posterity,offspring", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "死体", "Back": "corpse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下書き", "Back": "rough copy,draft", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "下町", "Back": "Shitamachi,lower parts of town", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "自治", "Back": "self-government,autonomy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実感", "Back": "feelings (actual, true)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "湿気", "Back": "moisture,humidity,dampness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しつこい", "Back": "insistent,obstinate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実習", "Back": "practice,training", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実績", "Back": "achievements,actual results", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "湿度", "Back": "level of humidity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "執筆", "Back": "writing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実物", "Back": "real thing,original", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しっぽ", "Back": "tail (animal)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実用", "Back": "practical use,utility", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実力", "Back": "merit,efficiency,arms,force", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実例", "Back": "example,illustration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "失恋", "Back": "disappointed love,broken heart,unrequited love,be lovelorn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "指定", "Back": "designation,specification,assignment,pointing at", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "私鉄", "Back": "private railway", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "児童", "Back": "children,juvenile", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縛る", "Back": "to tie,to bind", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地盤", "Back": "(the) ground", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しびれる", "Back": "to become numb,to go to sleep (i.e., a limb)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "紙幣", "Back": "paper money,notes,bills", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しぼむ", "Back": "to wither,to fade (away),to shrivel,to wilt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "絞る", "Back": "to press,to wring,to squeeze", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縞", "Back": "stripe", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地味", "Back": "plain,simple", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しみじみ", "Back": "keenly,deeply,heartily", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "氏名", "Back": "full name,identity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "締切", "Back": "closing,cut-off,end,deadline,Closed,No Entrance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "締め切る", "Back": "to shut up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "湿る", "Back": "to be wet,to become wet,to be damp", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ジャーナリスト", "Back": "journalist", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "社会科学", "Back": "social science", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しゃがむ", "Back": "to squat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蛇口", "Back": "faucet,tap", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "弱点", "Back": "weak point,weakness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "車庫", "Back": "garage,car shed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "車掌", "Back": "(train) conductor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "写生", "Back": "sketching,drawing from nature", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "社説", "Back": "editorial,leading article", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しゃっくり", "Back": "hiccough,hiccup", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "シャッター", "Back": "shutter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しゃぶる", "Back": "to suck,to chew", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "車輪", "Back": "(car) wheel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "洒落", "Back": "joke,pun,witticism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "じゃんけん", "Back": "(n) rock-scissors-paper game", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "集会", "Back": "meeting,assembly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "住居", "Back": "dwelling,house,residence,address", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "集金", "Back": "money collection", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "集合", "Back": "gathering,assembly,meeting,set (math)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "習字", "Back": "penmanship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "修繕", "Back": "repair,mending", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重体", "Back": "seriously ill,serious condition,critical state", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "じゅうたん", "Back": "carpet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "終点", "Back": "terminus,last stop (e.g train)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重点", "Back": "important point,lay stress on,colon,emphasis", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "就任", "Back": "inauguration,assumption of office", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "周辺", "Back": "circumference,outskirts,environs,(computer) peripheral", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重役", "Back": "director,high executive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "終了", "Back": "end,close,termination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重量", "Back": "(1) weight,(2) heavyweight boxer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "重力", "Back": "gravity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "熟語", "Back": "idiom,idiomatic phrase,kanji compound", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "祝日", "Back": "national holiday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縮小", "Back": "reduction,curtailment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "受験", "Back": "taking an examination", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主語", "Back": "(gram) subject", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出勤", "Back": "going to work,at work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "述語", "Back": "predicate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出張", "Back": "official tour,business trip", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寿命", "Back": "life span", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "主役", "Back": "leading part,leading actor (actress)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "受話器", "Back": "(telephone) receiver", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "循環", "Back": "circulation,rotation,cycle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "巡査", "Back": "police,policeman", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "順々", "Back": "in order,in turn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "順序", "Back": "order,sequence,procedure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "純情", "Back": "pure heart,naivete,self-sacrificing devotion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "純粋", "Back": "pure,true,genuine,unmixed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "消化", "Back": "digestion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小学生", "Back": "grade school student", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "しょうがない", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "将棋", "Back": "Japanese chess", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蒸気", "Back": "steam,vapour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "定規", "Back": "(measuring) ruler", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上級", "Back": "advanced level,high grade,senior", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "商業", "Back": "commerce,trade,business", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "消極的", "Back": "passive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賞金", "Back": "prize,monetary award", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上下", "Back": "high and low,up and down,unloading and loading,praising and blaming", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "障子", "Back": "paper sliding door", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "商社", "Back": "trading company,firm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乗車", "Back": "taking a train,entraining", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上旬", "Back": "first 10 days of month", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生ずる", "Back": "to cause,to arise,to be generated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小数", "Back": "fraction (part of),decimal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "商店", "Back": "shop,business firm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "焦点", "Back": "focus,point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "消毒", "Back": "disinfection,sterilization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勝敗", "Back": "victory or defeat,issue (of battle)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蒸発", "Back": "evaporation,unexplained disappearance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "賞品", "Back": "prize,trophy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "勝負", "Back": "victory or defeat,match,contest,game,bout", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "小便", "Back": "(col) urine,piss", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "消防署", "Back": "fire station", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正味", "Back": "net (weight)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正面", "Back": "the front,honesty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "消耗", "Back": "exhaustion,consumption", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "醤油", "Back": "soy sauce", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "省略", "Back": "omission,abbreviation,abridgment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "初級", "Back": "elementary level", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "助教授", "Back": "assistant professor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "食塩", "Back": "table salt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "職人", "Back": "worker,mechanic,artisan,craftsman", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "初旬", "Back": "first 10 days of the month", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "書籍", "Back": "book,publication", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "食器", "Back": "tableware", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ショップ", "Back": "a shop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "書店", "Back": "bookshop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "書道", "Back": "calligraphy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "白髪", "Back": "white or grey hair,trendy hair bleaching", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "知合い", "Back": "acquaintance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "シリーズ", "Back": "series", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "私立", "Back": "private (establishment)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "資料", "Back": "materials,data", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "汁", "Back": "juice,sap,soup,broth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "素人", "Back": "amateur,novice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "芯", "Back": "core,heart,wick,marrow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "新幹線", "Back": "bullet train (very high speed),shinkansen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真空", "Back": "vacuum,hollow,empty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "信ずる", "Back": "to believe,to believe in,to place trust in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "心身", "Back": "mind and body", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "申請", "Back": "application,request,petition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人造", "Back": "man-made,synthetic,artificial", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寝台", "Back": "bed,couch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "診断", "Back": "diagnosis", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "侵入", "Back": "penetration,invasion,raid,aggression,trespass", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人文科学", "Back": "social sciences,humanities", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人命", "Back": "(human) life", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "深夜", "Back": "late at night", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "森林", "Back": "forest,woods", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "親類", "Back": "relation,kin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "針路", "Back": "course,direction,compass bearing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "神話", "Back": "myth,legend", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "酢", "Back": "vinegar", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水産", "Back": "marine products,fisheries", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "炊事", "Back": "cooking,culinary arts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水蒸気", "Back": "water vapour,steam", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水素", "Back": "hydrogen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "垂直", "Back": "vertical,perpendicular", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "推定", "Back": "presumption,assumption,estimation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水滴", "Back": "drop of water", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水筒", "Back": "canteen,flask,water bottle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "随筆", "Back": "essays,miscellaneous writings", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水分", "Back": "moisture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水平", "Back": "water level,horizon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水平線", "Back": "horizon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "水曜", "Back": "Wednesday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ずうずうしい", "Back": "impudent,shameless", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ずうっと", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "末っ子", "Back": "youngest child", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スカーフ", "Back": "scarf", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "図鑑", "Back": "picture book", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "杉", "Back": "Japanese cedar", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "好き嫌い", "Back": "likes and dislikes,taste", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "好き好き", "Back": "matter of taste", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "透き通る", "Back": "to be(come) transparent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "隙間", "Back": "crevice,crack,gap,opening", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スクール", "Back": "school", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "すくなくとも", "Back": "at least", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "図形", "Back": "figure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スケジュール", "Back": "schedule", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鈴", "Back": "bell", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "涼む", "Back": "to cool oneself,to cool off,to enjoy evening cool", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スタート", "Back": "start", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スチュワーデス", "Back": "stewardess", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "すっきり", "Back": "shapely,clear,neat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "すっぱい", "Back": "sour,acid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ステージ", "Back": "(1) stage,(2) performance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "棄てる", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ストッキング", "Back": "stockings", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ストップ", "Back": "stop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "素直", "Back": "obedient,meek,docile,unaffected", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頭脳", "Back": "head,brains,intellect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スピーカー", "Back": "speaker", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "図表", "Back": "chart,diagram,graph", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スマート", "Back": "smart,stylish,slim", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "住まい", "Back": "dwelling,house,residence,address", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "すまない", "Back": "sorry (phrase)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "墨", "Back": "ink", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "澄む", "Back": "to clear (e.g. weather),to become transparent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "清む", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "相撲", "Back": "sumo wrestling", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "スライド", "Back": "slide", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ずらす", "Back": "to put off,to delay", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ずらり", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掏摸", "Back": "pickpocket", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "刷る", "Back": "to print", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "狡い", "Back": "sly,cunning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "すれちがう", "Back": "to pass by one another,to disagree", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "滑れる", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寸法", "Back": "measurement,size,dimension", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "姓", "Back": "surname,family name", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "税関", "Back": "customs house", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "製作", "Back": "manufacture,production", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "制作", "Back": "work (film, book)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "性質", "Back": "nature,property,disposition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "清書", "Back": "clean copy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "青少年", "Back": "youth,young person", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "整数", "Back": "integer", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "清掃", "Back": "cleaning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生存", "Back": "existence,being,survival", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生長", "Back": "growth,increment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "政党", "Back": "(member of) political party", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生年月日", "Back": "birth date", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "性能", "Back": "ability,efficiency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "整備", "Back": "adjustment,completion,consolidation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "成分", "Back": "ingredient,component,composition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "性別", "Back": "distinction by sex,sex,gender", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正方形", "Back": "square", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "正門", "Back": "main gate,main entrance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "成立", "Back": "coming into existence,arrangements,establishment,completion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "西暦", "Back": "Christian Era,anno domini (A.D.)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "背負う", "Back": "to be burdened with,to carry on back or shoulder", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "赤道", "Back": "equator", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "折角", "Back": "with trouble,at great pains,long-awaited", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "接近", "Back": "getting closer,drawing nearer,approaching", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "石鹸", "Back": "soap", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "接する", "Back": "to come in contact with,to connect,to attend,to receive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "せっせと", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "接続", "Back": "(1) connection,union,join,link,(2) changing trains", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "瀬戸物", "Back": "earthenware,crockery,china", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぜひとも", "Back": "by all means (with sense of not taking no for an answer)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "迫る", "Back": "to draw near,to press", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ゼミ", "Back": "(n) seminar", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "せめて", "Back": "offense,method of attack", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "攻める", "Back": "to attack,to assault", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "セメント", "Back": "cement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "栓", "Back": "stopper,cork,stopcock", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "前後", "Back": "around,throughout,front and back,before and behind,before and after", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "洗剤", "Back": "detergent,washing material", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "全集", "Back": "complete works", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "全身", "Back": "the whole body,full-length (portrait)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "扇子", "Back": "folding fan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "専制", "Back": "despotism,autocracy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先々月", "Back": "month before last", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先々週", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先祖", "Back": "ancestor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先端", "Back": "pointed end,tip,fine point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "センチ", "Back": "centimeter,centi-,10^-2", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "宣伝", "Back": "propaganda,publicity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "先頭", "Back": "head,lead,vanguard,first", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "全般", "Back": "(the) whole,universal,wholly,general", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "扇風機", "Back": "electric fan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "線路", "Back": "line,track,roadbed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "相違", "Back": "difference,discrepancy,variation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そういえば", "Back": "which reminds me ..", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "雑巾", "Back": "house-cloth,dust cloth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "増減", "Back": "increase and decrease,fluctuation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "倉庫", "Back": "storehouse,warehouse,godown", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "相互", "Back": "mutual,reciprocal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "創作", "Back": "production,literary creation,work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "葬式", "Back": "funeral", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そうして", "Back": "and,like that", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "造船", "Back": "shipbuilding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "騒々しい", "Back": "noisy,boisterous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "増大", "Back": "enlargement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そうっと", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "送別", "Back": "farewell,send-off", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "草履", "Back": "zoori (Japanese footwear),sandals", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "総理大臣", "Back": "Prime Minister", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "送料", "Back": "postage,carriage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "属する", "Back": "to belong to,to come under,to be affiliated with,to be subject to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "続々", "Back": "successively,one after another", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "速達", "Back": "express,special delivery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "測定", "Back": "measurement", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "測量", "Back": "measurement,surveying", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "速力", "Back": "speed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "素質", "Back": "character,qualities,genius", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "祖先", "Back": "ancestor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そそっかしい", "Back": "careless,thoughtless", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "卒直", "Back": "frankness,candour,openheartedness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "具える", "Back": "to be furnished with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そのうえ", "Back": "in addition,furthermore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そのころ", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そのため", "Back": "hence,for that reason", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "そのほか", "Back": "otherwise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蕎麦", "Back": "soba (buckwheat noodles)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "剃る", "Back": "to shave", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "それなのに", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逸れる", "Back": "to stray (turn) from subject,to get lost,to go astray", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "揃う", "Back": "to become complete,to be equal,to be all present,to gather", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "揃える", "Back": "to put things in order,to arrange,to make uniform,to get something ready", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "算盤", "Back": "abacus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "存じる", "Back": "(hum) to know", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "存ずる", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "損得", "Back": "loss and gain,advantage and disadvantage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "田ぼ", "Back": "paddy field,farm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "だいいち", "Back": "first,foremost,# 1", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "退院", "Back": "leaving hospital", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大学院", "Back": "graduate school", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大工", "Back": "carpenter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "体系", "Back": "system,organization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "太鼓", "Back": "drum,tambourine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対策", "Back": "counter-plan,counter-measure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大して", "Back": "(not so) much,(not) very", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "対照", "Back": "contrast,antithesis,comparison", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大小", "Back": "size", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "体制", "Back": "order,system,structure,set-up,organization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "体積", "Back": "capacity,volume", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大層", "Back": "very much,exaggerated,very fine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "体操", "Back": "gymnastics,physical exercises,calisthenics", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大分", "Back": "considerably,greatly,a lot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "大木", "Back": "large tree", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "題名", "Back": "title", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "代名詞", "Back": "pronoun", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "タイア", "Back": "tire,tyre", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ダイヤグラム", "Back": "diagram", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ダイヤモンド", "Back": "diamond", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ダイヤル", "Back": "dial", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "Ͼ立", "Back": "confrontation,opposition,antagonism", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "田植え", "Back": "rice planting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "絶えず", "Back": "constantly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "楕円", "Back": "ellipse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "高める", "Back": "to raise,to lift,to boost", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "耕す", "Back": "to till,to plow,to cultivate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "滝", "Back": "waterfall", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "炊く", "Back": "to boil,to cook", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "焚く", "Back": "to burn,to kindle,to build a fire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蓄える", "Back": "to store,to lay in stock", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "竹", "Back": "bamboo,middle (of a three-tier ranking system)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "助かる", "Back": "to be saved,to be rescued,to survive,to be helpful", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "只", "Back": "free of charge,mere,sole,only,usual,common", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "但し", "Back": "but,however,provided that", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "畳む", "Back": "to fold (clothes)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "立ち止まる", "Back": "to stop,to halt,to stand still", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "たちまち", "Back": "at once,in a moment,suddenly,all at once", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "建つ", "Back": "to erect,to be erected,to be built", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発つ", "Back": "to depart (on a plane, train, etc.)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "脱線", "Back": "derailment,digression", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "妥当", "Back": "valid,proper,right,appropriate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "例える", "Back": "to compare,to liken,to speak figuratively,to illustrate,to use a simile", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頼もしい", "Back": "reliable,trustworthy,hopeful,promising", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "足袋", "Back": "tabi,Japanese socks (with split toe)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ダブル", "Back": "double", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "だます", "Back": "to trick,to cheat,to deceive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "溜まる", "Back": "to collect,to gather,to save", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ダム", "Back": "dumb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "溜息", "Back": "a sigh", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ためらう", "Back": "to hesitate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "溜める", "Back": "to amass,to accumulate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "だらしない", "Back": "slovenly,loose,a slut", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "足る", "Back": "to be sufficient,to be enough", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "段階", "Back": "gradation,grade,stage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "短期", "Back": "short term", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "炭鉱", "Back": "coal mine,coal pit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "短所", "Back": "(1) defect,demerit,weak point,(2) disadvantage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "たんす", "Back": "chest of drawers", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "淡水", "Back": "fresh water", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "断水", "Back": "water outage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "単数", "Back": "singular (number)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "団地", "Back": "multi-unit apartments", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "断定", "Back": "conclusion,decision", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "短編", "Back": "short (e.g. story, film)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "誓う", "Back": "to swear,to vow,to take an oath,to pledge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地下水", "Back": "underground water", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "近々", "Back": "nearness,before long", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "近付ける", "Back": "to bring near,to put close,to let come near,to associate with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "近寄る", "Back": "to approach,to draw near", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "力強い", "Back": "reassuring,emboldened", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ちぎる", "Back": "to cut up fine,to pick (fruit)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地質", "Back": "geological features", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "知人", "Back": "friend,acquaintance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地帯", "Back": "area,zone", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縮む", "Back": "to shrink,to be contracted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縮める", "Back": "to shorten,to reduce,to boil down,to shrink", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縮れる", "Back": "to be wavy,to be curled", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "チップ", "Back": "(1) gratuity,tip,(2) chip", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地点", "Back": "site,point on a map", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "地名", "Back": "place name", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "茶色い", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "着々", "Back": "steadily", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "茶碗", "Back": "rice bowl,tea cup,teacup", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中間", "Back": "middle,midway,interim", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中旬", "Back": "second third of a month", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "抽象", "Back": "abstract", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中世", "Back": "Middle Ages,mediaeval times", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中性", "Back": "neuter gender,neutral (chem.),indifference,sterility", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中途", "Back": "in the middle,half-way", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中年", "Back": "middle-aged", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "超過", "Back": "excess,being more than", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "彫刻", "Back": "carving,engraving,sculpture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "長所", "Back": "(1) strong point,merit,(2) advantage", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "長女", "Back": "eldest daughter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "調整", "Back": "regulation,adjustment,tuning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "調節", "Back": "regulation,adjustment,control", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "長短", "Back": "length,long and short,+-", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "頂点", "Back": "top,summit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "長男", "Back": "eldest son", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "長方形", "Back": "rectangle,oblong", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "調味料", "Back": "condiment,seasoning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "チョーク", "Back": "chock,chalk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直後", "Back": "immediately following", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直線", "Back": "straight line", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直前", "Back": "just before", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直通", "Back": "direct communication", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直流", "Back": "direct current", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "貯蔵", "Back": "storage,preservation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直角", "Back": "right angle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "直径", "Back": "diameter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "散らかる", "Back": "to be in disorder,to lie scattered around", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "散らかす", "Back": "to scatter around,to leave untidy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "散らす", "Back": "to scatter,to disperse,to distribute", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "塵紙", "Back": "tissue paper,toilet paper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "散る", "Back": "to fall,to scatter (e.g. blossoms)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "追加", "Back": "addition,supplement,appendix", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ついで", "Back": "opportunity,occasion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通貨", "Back": "currency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通勤", "Back": "commuting to work", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通ずる", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通知", "Back": "notice,notification", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通訳", "Back": "interpretation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通帳", "Back": "passbook", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通用", "Back": "popular use,circulation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通路", "Back": "passage,pathway", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "付合う", "Back": "to associate with,to keep company with,to get on with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "突き当たり", "Back": "end (e.g. of street)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "突き当たる", "Back": "to run into,to collide with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "月日", "Back": "time,years,days", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "点く", "Back": "to catch fire,(electricity) comes on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "突く", "Back": "(1) to thrust,to strike,(2) to poke", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "次ぐ", "Back": "to rank next to,to come after", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "作る/造る", "Back": "to make,to create", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "着ける", "Back": "(1) to attach,to join,to add,to append", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "点ける", "Back": "to turn on,to switch on,to light up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浸ける", "Back": "to dip in,to soak", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伝わる", "Back": "to be handed down,to be introduced,to be transmitted", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "突っ込む", "Back": "to plunge into,to go into deeply", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "務める", "Back": "(1) to serve,to fill a post,to serve under,to work (for)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "努める", "Back": "(1) to serve,to fill a post,to serve under,to work (for)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "綱", "Back": "rope", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "繋がり", "Back": "connection,link,relationship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "繋がる", "Back": "to be tied together,to be connected to,to be related to", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "繋げる", "Back": "to connect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "粒", "Back": "grain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "潰す", "Back": "to smash,to waste", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "潰れる", "Back": "to be smashed,to go bankrupt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "つまずく", "Back": "to stumble,to trip", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "詰まる", "Back": "to be blocked,to be packed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "積む", "Back": "to pile up,to stack", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "爪", "Back": "fingernail or toenail,claw,talon,hoof", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "艶", "Back": "gloss,glaze", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "強気", "Back": "firm,strong", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "釣り合う", "Back": "to balance,to be in harmony,to suit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吊る", "Back": "to hang", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吊す", "Back": "to hang", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出合い", "Back": "an encounter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手洗い", "Back": "restroom,lavatory,hand-washing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "定員", "Back": "fixed number of regular personnel,capacity (of boat, etc.)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "定価", "Back": "established price", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "低下", "Back": "fall,decline,lowering,deterioration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "定期券", "Back": "commuter pass,season ticket", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "定休日", "Back": "regular holiday", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "停止", "Back": "suspension,interruption,stoppage,ban", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "停車", "Back": "stopping (e.g. train)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "停電", "Back": "failure of electricity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出入り", "Back": "in and out,coming and going,free association,income and expenditure,debits and credit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出入口", "Back": "exit and entrance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手入れ", "Back": "repairs,maintenance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "テーマ", "Back": "(n) theme,project,topic (de: Thema)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出掛ける", "Back": "to depart,to set out,to start,to be going out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出来上がり", "Back": "be finished,ready,made for,cut out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出来上がる", "Back": "(1) to be finished,to be ready,by definition,(2) to be very drunk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "的確", "Back": "precise,accurate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "適確", "Back": "precise,accurate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手首", "Back": "wrist", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "凸凹", "Back": "unevenness,roughness,ruggedness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手頃", "Back": "moderate,handy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "でたらめ", "Back": "(1) irresponsible utterance,nonsense,nonsensical,(2) random", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手帳", "Back": "notebook", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鉄橋", "Back": "railway bridge,iron bridge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手続き", "Back": "procedure,(legal) process,formalities", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鉄砲", "Back": "gun", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "テニスコート", "Back": "tennis court", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手拭い", "Back": "(hand) towel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "手前", "Back": "before,this side,we,you", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出迎え", "Back": "meeting,reception", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "出迎える", "Back": "to meet,to greet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "照らす", "Back": "to shine on,to illuminate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "照る", "Back": "to shine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "展開", "Back": "develop,expansion (opposite of compression)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伝記", "Back": "biography,life story", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "電球", "Back": "light bulb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "点数", "Back": "marks,points,score,runs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "伝染", "Back": "contagion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "電池", "Back": "battery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "点々", "Back": "here and there,little by little", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "転々", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "電柱", "Back": "telephone pole,telegraph pole,lightpole", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "天皇", "Back": "Emperor of Japan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "電波", "Back": "electro-magnetic wave", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "テンポ", "Back": "tempo", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "電流", "Back": "electric current", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "電力", "Back": "electric power", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "問い合わせ", "Back": "enquiry,ENQ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "銅", "Back": "copper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "統一", "Back": "unity,consolidation,uniformity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "同格", "Back": "the same rank,equality,apposition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "峠", "Back": "ridge,(mountain) pass,difficult part", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "統計", "Back": "scattering,a scatter,dispersion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "動作", "Back": "action,movements,motions,bearing,behaviour,manners", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "東西", "Back": "East and West,whole country", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "当日", "Back": "appointed day,very day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "投書", "Back": "letter to the editor,letter from a reader,contribution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "登場", "Back": "entry (on stage)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どうせ", "Back": "anyhow,in any case,at any rate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どうぞよろしく", "Back": "pleased to meet you", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "灯台", "Back": "lighthouse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "盗難", "Back": "theft,robbery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "当番", "Back": "being on duty", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "等分", "Back": "division into equal parts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "透明", "Back": "transparency,cleanness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "灯油", "Back": "lamp oil,kerosene", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "東洋", "Back": "Orient", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "童話", "Back": "fairy tale", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "通り掛かる", "Back": "to happen to pass by", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "溶かす", "Back": "to melt,to dissolve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "尖る", "Back": "to taper to a point,to become sharp,to be sour,to look displeased", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どきどき", "Back": "throb,beat (fast)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "溶く", "Back": "to dissolve (paint)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "退く", "Back": "(1) to retreat,to recede,to withdraw", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "特殊", "Back": "special,unique", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "特色", "Back": "characteristic,feature", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "特長", "Back": "forte,merit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "特定", "Back": "specific,special,particular", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "特売", "Back": "special sale", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "溶け込む", "Back": "to melt into", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "溶ける", "Back": "to melt,to thaw,to fuse,to dissolve", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "退ける", "Back": "to remove,to take away,to dislodge,to put something out of the way", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "床の間", "Back": "alcove", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "床屋", "Back": "barber", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "所々", "Back": "here and there,some parts (of something)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "都心", "Back": "heart (of city)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "戸棚", "Back": "cupboard,locker,closet,wardrobe", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "とっくに", "Back": "long ago,already,a long time ago", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どっと", "Back": "suddenly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "整う", "Back": "to be prepared,to be in order,to be put in order,to be arranged", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "留まる", "Back": "(1) to be fixed,(2) to abide,to stay (in the one place)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "どなる", "Back": "to shout,to yell", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "飛び込む", "Back": "to jump in,to leap in,to plunge into,to dive", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "跳ぶ", "Back": "to jump,to fly,to leap", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "泊める", "Back": "to give shelter to,to lodge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ともかく", "Back": "anyhow,anyway,somehow or other,generally speaking,in any case", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捕える", "Back": "to seize,to grasp,to capture,to arrest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り入れる", "Back": "to harvest,to take in,to adopt", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り消す", "Back": "to cancel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "取り出す", "Back": "to take out,to produce,to pick out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "採る", "Back": "(1) to adopt (measure, proposal),(2) to pick (fruit)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捕る", "Back": "to take,to catch (fish),to capture", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "トレーニング", "Back": "training", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "丼", "Back": "porcelain bowl,bowl of rice with food on top", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "内科", "Back": "internist clinic,internal medicine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "内線", "Back": "phone extension,indoor wiring,inner line", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ナイロン", "Back": "nylon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "治す", "Back": "to cure,to heal,to fix,to correct,to repair", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "永い", "Back": "long,lengthy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仲直り", "Back": "reconciliation,make peace with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "長引く", "Back": "to be prolonged,to drag on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中身", "Back": "contents,interior,substance,filling,(sword) blade", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中味", "Back": "contents,interior,substance,filling,(sword) blade", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "中指", "Back": "middle finger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "仲良し", "Back": "intimate friend,bosom buddy,chum", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慰める", "Back": "to comfort,to console", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "亡くす", "Back": "to lose someone, wife, child, etc", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "なぐる", "Back": "to strike,to hit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "為す", "Back": "to accomplish,to do", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "謎謎", "Back": "riddle,puzzle,enigma", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "傾らか", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "懐かしい", "Back": "dear,desired,missed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "撫でる", "Back": "to brush gently,to stroke", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "斜め", "Back": "obliqueness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "なにしろ", "Back": "at any rate,anyhow,anyway,in any case", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何々", "Back": "such and such,What?", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "何分", "Back": "what minute?,how many minutes?", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生意気", "Back": "impertinent,saucy,cheeky,conceit,audacious,brazen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "並木", "Back": "roadside tree,row of trees", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "倣う", "Back": "to imitate,to follow,to emulate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鳴らす", "Back": "to ring,to sound,to chime,to beat,to snort (nose)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生る", "Back": "to bear fruit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "馴れる", "Back": "to become domesticated,to become tame", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "南極", "Back": "south pole,Antarctic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "なんとなく", "Back": "somehow or other,for some reason or another", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "なんとも", "Back": "nothing (with neg. verb),quite,not a bit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ナンバー", "Back": "number", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "南米", "Back": "South America", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "南北", "Back": "south and north", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煮える", "Back": "to boil,to cook,to be cooked", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "匂う", "Back": "to be fragrant,to smell,to stink", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "逃がす", "Back": "to let loose,to set free,to let escape", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "憎い", "Back": "hateful,abominable,poor-looking,detestable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "憎む", "Back": "to hate,to detest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "憎らしい", "Back": "odious,hateful", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "にこにこ", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "濁る", "Back": "to become muddy,to get impure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "虹", "Back": "rainbow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日時", "Back": "date and time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日用品", "Back": "daily necessities", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日課", "Back": "daily lesson,daily work,daily routine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日程", "Back": "agenda", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鈍い", "Back": "dull (e.g. a knife),thickheaded,slow (opposite of fast),stupid", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "入社", "Back": "entry to a company", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "女房", "Back": "wife", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "睨む", "Back": "to glare at,to scowl at,to keep an eye on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煮る", "Back": "to boil,to cook", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "俄", "Back": "sudden,abrupt,unexpected,improvised,offhand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "縫う", "Back": "to sew", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "濡らす", "Back": "to wet,to soak,to dip", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ねじ", "Back": "(a) screw", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捩る", "Back": "to twist", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ネックレス", "Back": "necklace", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "熱する", "Back": "to heat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寝間着", "Back": "sleep-wear,nightclothes,pyjamas,nightgown,nightdress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寝巻", "Back": "sleep-wear,nightclothes,pyjamas,nightgown,nightdress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "狙い", "Back": "aim", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "狙う", "Back": "to aim at", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "年度", "Back": "year,fiscal year,school year,term", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "農産物", "Back": "agricultural produce", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "農村", "Back": "agricultural community,farm village,rural", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "濃度", "Back": "concentration,brightness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "農薬", "Back": "agricultural chemicals", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "能率", "Back": "efficiency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "のこぎり", "Back": "saw", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "残らず", "Back": "all,entirely,completely,without exception", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "載せる", "Back": "to place on (something),to take on board,to give a ride", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "覗く", "Back": "to peep in,to look in,to peek in,to stick out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "延ばす", "Back": "to lengthen,to stretch,to reach out,to grow (beard)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "延びる", "Back": "to be prolonged", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上り", "Back": "up-train (going to Tokyo),ascent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "上る", "Back": "to ascend,to go up,to climb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "糊", "Back": "paste,starch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乗換", "Back": "(n) transfer (trains, buses, etc.)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "載る", "Back": "to appear (in print),to be recorded", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "のろのろ", "Back": "slowly,sluggishly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "呑気", "Back": "carefree,optimistic,careless,reckless,heedless", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "灰色", "Back": "grey,gray,ashen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "俳句", "Back": "haiku poetry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拝見", "Back": "(hum) (pol) seeing,look at", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "売店", "Back": "shop,stand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "バイバイ", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "売買", "Back": "trade,buying and selling", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "這う", "Back": "to creep,to crawl", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "生える", "Back": "(1) to grow,to spring up,(2) to cut (teeth)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "剥す", "Back": "(v5s) to tear off,to peel off,to rip off", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ばからしい", "Back": "absurd", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "秤", "Back": "scales,weighing machine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "量る", "Back": "to measure,to weigh,to survey", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "測る", "Back": "to measure,to weigh,to survey", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吐き気", "Back": "nausea,sickness in the stomach", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "はきはき", "Back": "lucidly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掃く", "Back": "to sweep,to brush,to gather up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歯車", "Back": "gear,cog-wheel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "バケツ", "Back": "bucket,pail", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "挟まる", "Back": "to get between,to be caught in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "挟む", "Back": "to interpose,to hold between,to insert", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "箸", "Back": "chopsticks", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "梯子", "Back": "ladder,stairs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "始めに", "Back": "to begin with,first of all", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "初めに", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "はじめまして", "Back": "How do you do?,I am glad to meet you", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "斜", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "外れる", "Back": "to be disconnected,to get out of place,to be off,to be out (e.g. of gear)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "パターン", "Back": "pattern", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "肌着", "Back": "underwear", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "果して", "Back": "as was expected,really", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "鉢", "Back": "a bowl,a pot", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "×", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発揮", "Back": "exhibition,demonstration,utilization,display", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "バック", "Back": "back", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発射", "Back": "firing,shooting,discharge,catapult", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発想", "Back": "expression (music),conceptualization", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発電", "Back": "generation (e.g. power)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "発売", "Back": "sale", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "派手", "Back": "showy,loud,gay,flashy,gaudy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "話合い", "Back": "discussion,conference", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "話し掛ける", "Back": "to accost a person,to talk (to someone)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "話中", "Back": "while talking,the line is busy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "甚だしい", "Back": "extreme,excessive,terrible", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "花火", "Back": "fireworks", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "花嫁", "Back": "bride", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "放れる", "Back": "to leave,to get free,to cut oneself off", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "羽根", "Back": "shuttlecock", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ばね", "Back": "spring (e.g. coil, leaf)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "跳ねる", "Back": "to jump,to leap", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "破片", "Back": "fragment,splinter,broken piece", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "歯磨き", "Back": "dentifrice,toothpaste", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "はめる", "Back": "(col) to get in,to insert,to put on,to make love", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "早口", "Back": "fast-talking", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "流行る", "Back": "to flourish,to thrive,to be popular,to come into fashion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "払い込む", "Back": "to deposit,to pay in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "払い戻す", "Back": "to repay,to pay back", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "バランス", "Back": "balance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "針金", "Back": "wire", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "張り切る", "Back": "to be in high spirits,to be full of vigor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反映", "Back": "reflection,influence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "半径", "Back": "radius", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "判子", "Back": "seal (used for signature)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "万歳", "Back": "hurrah, cheers", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "判事", "Back": "judge,judiciary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "反省", "Back": "reflection,reconsideration,introspection,meditation,contemplation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "番地", "Back": "house number,address", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "パンツ", "Back": "underpants", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "バンド", "Back": "band", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "半島", "Back": "peninsula", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ハンドル", "Back": "handle,steering wheel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日当たり", "Back": "exposure to the sun,sunny place", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日帰り", "Back": "day trip", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "比較的", "Back": "comparatively,relatively", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日陰", "Back": "shadow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぴかぴか", "Back": "glitter,sparkle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引受る", "Back": "to undertake,to take up,to take over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引返す", "Back": "to repeat,to send back,to bring back", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引算", "Back": "subtraction", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引出す", "Back": "to pull out,to take out,to draw out,to withdraw", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引き止める", "Back": "to detain,to check,to restrain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "卑怯", "Back": "cowardice,meanness,unfairness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引分け", "Back": "a draw (in competition),tie game", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "髭", "Back": "moustache,beard,whiskers", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "陽射", "Back": "sunlight,rays of the sun", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "肘", "Back": "elbow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ピストル", "Back": "pistol", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ビタミン", "Back": "vitamin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぴたり", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引っ掛かる", "Back": "to be caught in,to be stuck in,to be cheated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "筆記", "Back": "(taking) notes,copying", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引っ繰り返す", "Back": "to turn over,to overturn,to knock over,to upset,to turn inside out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引っ繰り返る", "Back": "to be overturned,to be upset,to topple over,to be reversed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引越し", "Back": "moving (dwelling etc.),changing residence", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "引っ込む", "Back": "to draw back,to sink,to cave in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "筆者", "Back": "writer,author", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "必需品", "Back": "necessities,necessary article,requisite,essential", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人差指", "Back": "index finger", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一通り", "Back": "ordinary,usual,in general,briefly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "人通り", "Back": "pedestrian traffic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ひとまず", "Back": "for the present,once,in outline", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "瞳", "Back": "pupil (of eye)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "一休み", "Back": "a rest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "独り言", "Back": "a soliloquy,a monologue,speaking to oneself", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ひとりでに", "Back": "by itself,automatically,naturally", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ビニール", "Back": "vinyl", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "皮肉", "Back": "cynicism,sarcasm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日日", "Back": "every day,daily,day after day", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "捻る", "Back": "to turn (a switch) on or off,to twist,to puzzle over", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日の入り", "Back": "sunset", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "日の出", "Back": "sunrise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "響き", "Back": "echo,sound,reverberation,noise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "響く", "Back": "to resound", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "皮膚", "Back": "skin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冷やす", "Back": "to cool,to refrigerate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ひゃっかじてん", "Back": "encyclopedia", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "美容", "Back": "beauty of figure or form", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "表紙", "Back": "front cover,binding", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "標識", "Back": "sign,mark", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "標準", "Back": "standard,level", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "標本", "Back": "example,specimen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "評論", "Back": "criticism,critique", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平仮名", "Back": "hiragana,47 syllables,the cursive syllabary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ビルディング", "Back": "building", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "昼寝", "Back": "nap (at home),siesta", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "広げる", "Back": "to spread,to extend,to expand,to enlarge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "広さ", "Back": "extent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "広場", "Back": "plaza", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "広々", "Back": "extensive,spacious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "広める", "Back": "to broaden,to propagate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ピンク", "Back": "pink", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "便箋", "Back": "writing paper,stationery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "瓶詰", "Back": "bottling,bottled", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ファスナー", "Back": "fastener,zipper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "風船", "Back": "balloon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不運", "Back": "unlucky,misfortune,bad luck,fate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "殖える", "Back": "to increase,to multiply", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "深まる", "Back": "to deepen,to heighten,to intensify", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不規則", "Back": "irregularity,unsteadiness,disorderly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "普及", "Back": "diffusion,spread", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "付近", "Back": "neighbourhood,vicinity,environs", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "拭く", "Back": "to wipe,to dry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "副詞", "Back": "adverb", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "複写", "Back": "copy,duplicate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "複数", "Back": "plural,multiple", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "含める", "Back": "to include,to instruct,to make one understand", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "膨らます", "Back": "to swell,to expand,to inflate,to bulge", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "膨らむ", "Back": "to expand,to swell (out),to get big,to become inflated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不潔", "Back": "unclean,dirty,filthy,impure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "更ける", "Back": "to get late,to advance,to wear on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "符号", "Back": "sign,mark,symbol", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夫妻", "Back": "man and wife,married couple", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "塞がる", "Back": "to be plugged up,to be shut up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "塞ぐ", "Back": "to stop up,to close up,to block (up)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ふざける", "Back": "to romp,to gambol,to frolic,to joke", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無沙汰", "Back": "neglecting to stay in contact", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "武士", "Back": "warrior,samurai", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "部首", "Back": "radical (of a kanji character)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "襖", "Back": "sliding screen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "附属", "Back": "attached,belonging,affiliated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蓋", "Back": "cover,lid,cap", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "不通", "Back": "suspension,interruption,stoppage,tie-up,cessation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぶつかる", "Back": "to strike,to collide with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぶつける", "Back": "to knock,to run into,to nail on,to strike hard,to hit and attack", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物騒", "Back": "dangerous,disturbed,insecure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぶつぶつ", "Back": "grumbling,complaining in a small voice", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "船便", "Back": "surface mail (ship)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "部品", "Back": "parts,accessories", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "吹雪", "Back": "snow storm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "父母", "Back": "father and mother,parents", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "踏切", "Back": "railway crossing,level crossing,starting line,scratch,crossover", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "麓", "Back": "the foot,the bottom,the base (of a mountain)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "増やす", "Back": "to increase,to add to,to augment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "殖やす", "Back": "to increase,to add to,to augment", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "フライパン", "Back": "fry pan,frying pan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ブラウス", "Back": "blouse", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぶらさげる", "Back": "to hang,to suspend,to dangle,to swing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ブラシ", "Back": "brushy,brush", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "プラスチック", "Back": "plastic", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "プラットホーム", "Back": "platform", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "フリー", "Back": "free", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "振り仮名", "Back": ",pronunciation key", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "プリント", "Back": "print,handout", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "振舞う", "Back": "to behave,to conduct oneself,to entertain (vt)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ブローチ", "Back": "brooch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "プログラム", "Back": "program", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "風呂敷", "Back": "wrapping cloth,cloth wrapper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ふわふわ", "Back": "light,soft", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "噴火", "Back": "eruption", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分解", "Back": "analysis,disassembly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "文芸", "Back": "literature,art and literature,belles-lettres", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "文献", "Back": "literature,books (reference)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "噴水", "Back": "water fountain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分数", "Back": "fraction (in math)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "文体", "Back": "literary style", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分布", "Back": "distribution", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "文房具", "Back": "stationery", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "文脈", "Back": "context", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分量", "Back": "amount,quantity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分類", "Back": "classification", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "閉会", "Back": "closure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平気", "Back": "coolness,calmness,composure,unconcern", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "並行", "Back": "(going) side by side,concurrent,abreast,at the same time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平日", "Back": "weekday,ordinary days", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "兵隊", "Back": "soldier,sailor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平凡", "Back": "common,commonplace,ordinary,mediocre", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "平野", "Back": "plain,open field", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "凹む", "Back": "to be dented,to be indented,to yield to,to give,to sink,to collapse,to cave in,to be snubbed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "へそ", "Back": "navel,belly-button", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "隔てる", "Back": "to be shut out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "別荘", "Back": "holiday house,villa", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "別々", "Back": "separately,individually", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ベテラン", "Back": "veteran", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ヘリコプター", "Back": "helicopter", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "へる", "Back": "to decrease (in size or number),to diminish,to abate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぺん", "Back": "pen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "編集", "Back": "editing,compilation,editorial (e.g. committee)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "便所", "Back": "toilet,lavatory,rest room,latrine,comfort station", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ペンチ", "Back": "(abbr) pliers (lit: pinchers)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "望遠鏡", "Back": "telescope", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "方角", "Back": "direction,way,compass point", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "箒", "Back": "(n) broom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "方言", "Back": "dialect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "坊さん", "Back": "Buddhist priest,monk", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "防止", "Back": "prevention,check", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "方針", "Back": "objective,plan,policy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "包装", "Back": "packing,wrapping", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "法則", "Back": "law,rule", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "包帯", "Back": "bandage,dressing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "膨大", "Back": "huge,bulky,enormous,extensive,swelling,expansion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "庖丁", "Back": "kitchen knife,carving knife", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "方程式", "Back": "equation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "防犯", "Back": "prevention of crime", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "方面", "Back": "direction,district,field (e.g., of study)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "坊や", "Back": "boy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "放る", "Back": "to let go", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ボーナス", "Back": "bonus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "朗らか", "Back": "brightness,cheerfulness,melodious", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "牧場", "Back": "(1) farm (livestock),(2) pasture land,meadow,grazing land", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "牧畜", "Back": "stock-farming", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "保健", "Back": "health preservation,hygiene,sanitation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "募集", "Back": "recruiting,taking applications", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "干す", "Back": "to air,to dry,to desiccate,to drain (off),to drink up", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ポスター", "Back": "poster", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "北極", "Back": "North Pole", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "坊っちゃん", "Back": "son (of others)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ほどく", "Back": "to unfasten", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "堀", "Back": "moat,canal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "掘る", "Back": "to dig,to excavate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "彫る", "Back": "to carve,to engrave,to sculpture,to chisel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ぼろ", "Back": "rag,scrap,tattered clothes,fault (esp. in a pretense)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "盆", "Back": "Lantern Festival,Festival of the Dead,tray", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "盆地", "Back": "basin (e.g. between mountains)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本部", "Back": "headquarters", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "本来", "Back": "essentially,naturally,by nature", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "まあまあ", "Back": "so-so", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "枚数", "Back": "the number of flat things", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "毎度", "Back": "each time,common service-sector greeting", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "マイナス", "Back": "minus", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "巻く", "Back": "to wind,to coil,to roll", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蒔く", "Back": "to sow (seeds)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "撒く", "Back": "to scatter,to sprinkle,to sow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "枕", "Back": "pillow,bolster", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "曲げる", "Back": "to bend,to crook,to lean", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "まごまご", "Back": "confused", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "摩擦", "Back": "friction,rubbing,rubdown,chafe", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "混ざる", "Back": "to be mixed,to be blended with,to associate with,to mingle with,to join", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交ざる", "Back": "to be mixed,to be blended with,to associate with,to mingle with,to join", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "混じる", "Back": "to be mixed,to be blended with,to associate with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交じる", "Back": "to be mixed,to be blended with,to associate with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "マスク", "Back": "mask", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "混ぜる", "Back": "to mix,to stir", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "交ぜる", "Back": "to be mixed,to be blended with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "またぐ", "Back": "to straddle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "又は", "Back": "or,otherwise", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "待合室", "Back": "waiting room", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "待ち合わせる", "Back": "to rendezvous,to meet at a prearranged place and time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "街角", "Back": "street corner", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真っ暗", "Back": "total darkness,shortsightedness,pitch dark", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真っ黒", "Back": "pitch black", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真っ青", "Back": "deep blue,ghastly pale", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真っ先", "Back": "the head,the foremost,beginning", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真っ白", "Back": "pure white", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "祭る", "Back": "to deify,to enshrine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "窓口", "Back": "ticket window", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "纏まる", "Back": "to be collected,to be settled,to be in order", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "纏める", "Back": "to put in order,to collect,to bring to a conclusion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "真似る", "Back": "to mimic,to imitate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "まぶしい", "Back": "dazzling,radiant", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "まぶた", "Back": "eyelids", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "マフラー", "Back": "muffler,scarf", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "間も無く", "Back": "soon,before long,in a short time", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "マラソン", "Back": "marathon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "円い", "Back": "round,circular,spherical", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "稀", "Back": "rare,seldom", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "回り道", "Back": "detour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "満員", "Back": "full house,no vacancy,sold out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "マンション", "Back": "large apartment,apartment house", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "満点", "Back": "perfect score", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見送る", "Back": "(1) to see off,to farewell,(2) to escort,(3) to let pass", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見下ろす", "Back": "to overlook,to command a view of,to look down on something", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見掛け", "Back": "outward appearance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "三日月", "Back": "new moon,crescent moon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "岬", "Back": "cape (on coast)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "みじめ", "Back": "(arch) sad,pitiful,wretched", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ミシン", "Back": "sewing machine", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "店屋", "Back": "store,shop", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見出し", "Back": "heading,caption,subtitle,index", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "道順", "Back": "itinerary,route", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見付かる", "Back": "to be found,to be discovered", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見付ける", "Back": "to be familiar,to discover,to detect", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "みっともない", "Back": "shameful,indecent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見直す", "Back": "to look again,to get a better opinion of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見慣れる", "Back": "to become used to seeing,to be familiar with", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "醜い", "Back": "ugly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "実る", "Back": "to bear fruit,to ripen", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "身分", "Back": "social position,social status", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見本", "Back": "sample", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "見舞う", "Back": "to ask after (health),to visit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "未満", "Back": "less than,insufficient", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名字", "Back": "surname,family name", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ミリ", "Back": "milli-,10^-3", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "診る", "Back": "to examine (medical)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "民間", "Back": "private,civilian,civil,popular,folk,unofficial", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "民謡", "Back": "folk song,popular song", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "向う", "Back": "(v5u) to face,to go towards", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "剥く", "Back": "to peel,to skin,to pare,to hull", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無限", "Back": "infinite", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無地", "Back": "plain,unfigured", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蒸し暑い", "Back": "humid,sultry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "矛盾", "Back": "contradiction,inconsistency", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蒸す", "Back": "to steam,to poultice,to be sultry", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "無数", "Back": "countless number,infinite number", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "紫", "Back": "purple colour,violet", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "群れ", "Back": "group,crowd,flock,herd", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "姪", "Back": "niece", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名作", "Back": "masterpiece", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名刺", "Back": "business card", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名詞", "Back": "noun", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名所", "Back": "famous place", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "命ずる", "Back": "to command,to appoint", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "迷信", "Back": "superstition", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "名物", "Back": "famous product,special product,speciality", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "銘々", "Back": "each,individual", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目上", "Back": "superior(s),senior", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "メーター", "Back": "meter (clock)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "恵まれる", "Back": "to be blessed with,to be rich in", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "巡る", "Back": "to go around", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目指す", "Back": "to aim at,to have an eye on", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目覚し", "Back": "(abbr) alarm-clock", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目下", "Back": "at present,now", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目印", "Back": "mark,sign,landmark", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目立つ", "Back": "to be conspicuous,to stand out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "めちゃくちゃ", "Back": "absurd,unreasonable,excessive,messed up,spoiled,wreaked", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "めっきり", "Back": "remarkably", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "めでたい", "Back": "happy,simple soul,propitious,joyous", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "メニュー", "Back": "menu", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "めまい", "Back": "dizziness,giddiness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目安", "Back": "criterion,aim", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "免税", "Back": "tax exemption,duty exemption", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "面積", "Back": "area", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "面接", "Back": "interview", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "面倒臭い", "Back": "bother to do,tiresome", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "儲かる", "Back": "to be profitable,to yield a profit", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "儲ける", "Back": "to get,to earn,to gain,to have (bear, beget) a child", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "申し訳ない", "Back": "inexcusable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "モーター", "Back": "motor", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "木材", "Back": "lumber,timber,wood", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "目次", "Back": "table of contents", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "潜る", "Back": "(1) to drive,to pass through,(2) to evade,to hide,(3) to dive (into or under water),to go undergroun", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "もしかしたら", "Back": "perhaps,maybe,by some chance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "もしかすると", "Back": "perhaps,maybe,by some chance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "もたれる", "Back": "to lean against,to lean on,to recline on,to lie heavy (on the stomach)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "モダン", "Back": "modern", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "餅", "Back": "sticky rice cake", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "もったいない", "Back": "too good,more than one deserves,wasteful,sacrilegious,unworthy of", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "モデル", "Back": "model", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "元々", "Back": "originally,by nature,from the start", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物置", "Back": "storage room", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物語る", "Back": "to tell,to indicate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物差し", "Back": "ruler,measure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "物凄い", "Back": "earth-shattering,staggering,to a very great extent", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "モノレール", "Back": "monorail", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "揉む", "Back": "to rub,to crumple (up),to wrinkle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "燃やす", "Back": "to burn", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "催し", "Back": "event,festivities,function", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "盛る", "Back": "(1) to serve (food, etc.),(2) to fill up,(3) to prescribe", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "問答", "Back": "questions and answers,dialogue", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "やかましい", "Back": "(1) noisy,(2) strict,fussy", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夜間", "Back": "at night,nighttime", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "薬缶", "Back": "kettle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "役者", "Back": "actor,actress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "役所", "Back": "government office,public office", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "訳す", "Back": "to translate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "役人", "Back": "government official", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "薬品", "Back": "medicine(s),chemical(s)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "役目", "Back": "duty,business", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "火傷", "Back": "burn,scald", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夜行", "Back": "walking around at night,night train,night travel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "矢印", "Back": "directing arrow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "やたらに", "Back": "randomly,recklessly,blindly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "薬局", "Back": "pharmacy,drugstore", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "やっつける", "Back": "to attack (an enemy),to beat,to do away with,to finish off", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "家主", "Back": "landlord", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "やっぱり", "Back": "also,as I thought,still,in spite of,absolutely,of course", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "破く", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "破れる", "Back": "to get torn,to wear out", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "やむをえない", "Back": "cannot be helped,unavoidable", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "軟らかい", "Back": "soft,tender,limp", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "遊園地", "Back": "amusement park", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夕刊", "Back": "evening paper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "友好", "Back": "friendship", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "郵送", "Back": "mailing", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夕立", "Back": "(sudden) evening shower (rain)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "夕日", "Back": "(in) the evening sun,setting sun", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "悠々", "Back": "quiet,calm,leisurely", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "有料", "Back": "admission-paid,toll", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "浴衣", "Back": "bathrobe,informal summer kimono,yukata", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "湯気", "Back": "steam,vapour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "輸血", "Back": "blood transfusion", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "輸送", "Back": "transport,transportation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "油断", "Back": "negligence,unpreparedness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ゆでる", "Back": "to boil", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "湯飲み", "Back": "teacup", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "緩い", "Back": "loose,lenient,slow", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "溶岩", "Back": "lava", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "容器", "Back": "container,vessel", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "用語", "Back": "term,terminology", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "要旨", "Back": "gist,essentials,summary,fundamentals", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幼児", "Back": "infant,baby,child", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "容積", "Back": "capacity,volume", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幼稚", "Back": "infancy,childish,infantile", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "幼稚園", "Back": "kindergarten", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "用途", "Back": "use,usefulness", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "洋品店", "Back": "shop which handles Western-style apparel and accessories", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "養分", "Back": "nourishment,nutrient", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "羊毛", "Back": "wool", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "漸く", "Back": "gradually,finally,hardly", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "要領", "Back": "point,gist,essentials,outline", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "欲張り", "Back": "avarice,covetousness,greed", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "余計", "Back": "too much,unnecessary,abundance,surplus,excess,superfluity", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "よこす", "Back": "(1) to send,to forward,(2) to hand over (e.g. money)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "汚す", "Back": "(1) to disgrace,to dishonour,(2) to pollute,to contaminate,to soil,to make dirty,to stain", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寄せる", "Back": "to collect,to gather,to add,to put aside", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "余所", "Back": "another place,somewhere else,strange parts", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "四つ角", "Back": "four corners,crossroads", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "酔っ払い", "Back": "drunkard", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "予備", "Back": "preparation,preliminaries,reserve,spare", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "呼び掛ける", "Back": "to call out to,to accost,to address (crowd),to appeal", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "呼び出す", "Back": "to summon,to call (e.g. phone)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蘇る", "Back": "to be resurrected,to be revived,to be resuscitated,to be rehabilitated", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "因る", "Back": "to come from", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慶び", "Back": "(n) (a) joy,(a) delight,rapture,pleasure,gratification,rejoicing,congratulations,felicitations", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "慶ぶ", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "来日", "Back": "arrival in Japan,coming to Japan,visit to Japan", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "落第", "Back": "failure,dropping out of a class", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ラッシュアワー", "Back": "rush hour", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "欄", "Back": "column of text (e.g. as in a newspaper)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ランチ", "Back": "launch,lunch", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ランニング", "Back": "(1) running,(2) tank top", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "乱暴", "Back": "rude,violent,rough,lawless,unreasonable,reckless", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "理科", "Back": "science", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "利害", "Back": "advantages and disadvantages,interest", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "リズム", "Back": "rhythm", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "リットル", "Back": "litre", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "リボン", "Back": "ribbon", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "略す", "Back": "to abbreviate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "流域", "Back": "(river) basin", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "寮", "Back": "hostel,dormitory", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "両側", "Back": "both sides", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "漁師", "Back": "fisherman", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "領事", "Back": "consul", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "領収", "Back": "receipt,voucher", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "臨時", "Back": "temporary,special,extraordinary", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "留守番", "Back": "care-taking,caretaker,house-watching", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "例外", "Back": "exception", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "零点", "Back": "zero,no marks", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "冷凍", "Back": "freezing,cold storage,refrigeration", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レインコート", "Back": "raincoat", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レクリェーション", "Back": "recreation", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レジャー", "Back": "leisure", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "列島", "Back": "chain of islands", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レベル", "Back": "level", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "リポート", "Back": "report,paper", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "煉瓦", "Back": "brick", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "連合", "Back": "union,alliance", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "レンズ", "Back": "lens", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "蝋燭", "Back": "candle", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ローマじ", "Back": "romanization,Roman letters", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "録音", "Back": "(audio) recording", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ロッカー", "Back": "locker", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ロビー", "Back": "lobby", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "論ずる", "Back": "to argue,to discuss,to debate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "和英", "Back": "Japanese-English", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分る", "Back": "to be understood", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "分かれる", "Back": "to branch off,to diverge from,to fork,to split,to dispense,to scatter,to divide into", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "若々しい", "Back": "youthful,young", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "湧く", "Back": "to boil,to grow hot,to get excited,to gush forth", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "詫びる", "Back": "to apologize", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "和服", "Back": "Japanese clothes", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "わりあいに", "Back": "comparatively", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "割算", "Back": "division (math)", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "割と", "Back": "relatively, comparitively", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "割引", "Back": "discount,reduction,rebate", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "椀", "Back": "Japanese soup bowl,wooden bowl", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "碗", "Back": "bowl", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{"Front": "ワンピース", "Back": "one-piece dress", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-eng"},
{}]
